

# SS

## SHIVESH SHANDILYA

#### **Professional Summary**

Experienced UI developer with a clear focus on front-end side of an application with primary skills in ReactJS, JavaScript, NodeJS HTML5, CSS3, Cypress with a demonstrated history of working in the Information Technology industry.

I have a total of 4+ years domain experience in Banking and Financial Services, ECOM Application development and Insurance Services.

#### **Work History**

Mphasis Limited | Senior Software Developer

Pune MH 12/2021 – Present (1 Year)

Client Name: American Insurance Group

#### Responsibilities and Contributions:

- Extensively worked on feature development using ReactJS, SASS, CSS, and JS.
- Worked on multiple features and developed components as per design and requirements.
- Worked on creation of Technical Design Documentation (TDD) to be presented to client for the feature.
- Resolved multiple bugs and helped in clearing backlogs.
- Worked on creating new AEM pages, deciding and developing its JSON according to the requirement.
- Worked on integrating API's for different use cases.
- Worked closely with design team for discussions and finalization of UI design for new features.
- Worked on Jest unit test cases for UI components and functionalities.

#### **IBM | Senior System Engineer**

Pune MH 01/2021 – 12/2021 (1 Year)

Client Name: Tiffany & Co.

## **Responsibilities and Contributions:**

- Extensively worked on front end, business and persistence tier using ReactJS, SASS, HTML, CSS, and Vanilla JS.
- Created multiple generic and customized reusable React Components.
- Involved in writing application-level code to interact with APIs, RESTful Web Services using AJAX, AXIOS, JSON.
- Analysed DOM Layout, DOM functions, JS functions, CSS across crossbrowser using Fire Bug and Developer Tool Bar.
- Created responsive react components easily rendered in all kinds of screens like desktop, tablets, mobile versions.
- Worked on optimising code quality, as well as application performance using Lighthouse tool.
- Used many different react packages like react-router, redux, slick, carousal, slider etc. to make the ECOM experience better.

## Tata Consultancy Services | System Engineer

Pune MH 06/2018 – 01/2021 (2 Years 7 months)

UI Developer | ReactJS Developer

Nov 2018 – 01/2021 Pune, India

Client Name: Barclays

## Responsibilities and Contributions:

- Carrying out Agile practices, requirements gathering, requirements analysis and estimation
- Working closely with product owner and other stakeholders.
- Developing user stories to enhance/add features as per client's requirements.
- Developed reusable components using ReactJS library.
- Used Apollo Client to make service calls to the GraphQL backend.
- Writing Cypress automation test scripts with a developer's point of view.
- Unit test cases and functional testing from developer's point of view to deliver in accordance to standards.
- Peer code review.
- Defect fixes for developed modules.
- Demo user stories to client stakeholders at the end of each sprint.

#### **Contact Details**

shivesh.shandilya1@gmail.com +91-7008011484/ +91-8017123243 2<sup>nd</sup> Floor, Sr. No. 3, Opposite Navratna Housing Society Lane No. 1, Wadgaon sheri, Pune-411014 India

#### **Technical Skills and Proficiencies**

- ReactJS
- CSS3
- HTML5
- JavaScript
- NodeJS
- graphQL
- ApolloClient
- SASS
- React Redux

#### **Tools and Softwares Used**

- Atlassian JIRA
- Confluence
- Zeplin
- Microsoft Azure Pipelines
- Visual Studio Code
- Git Bash
- Bit Bucket
- Source Code

## **Interpersonal Skills and Proficiencies**

- Teamwork
- Communication
- Client Interactions
- Leading a team
- Agile Methodology
- Requirement Gathering
- Technical Design Documentation

## **Education**

2018

**Techno India, Salt Lake** Kolkata, WB

**B.Tech: Electronics and Communication DGPA: 8.18** 

2013

St. Michael's High School Patna, Bihar Intermediate Marks (%): 89.4

## Hobbies

- Mobile Photography
- Charcoal Sketching
- Poem Writing
- Reading Novels

## Certifications

 Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals Issued: April 2021 Credential ID: H748-2905